MKN Kumar

Chief Executive Officer

mknkumarceo@gmail.com

(+91) 879-238-7826

linkedin.com/in/mkn-kumar-ceo

Professional Profile

Skilled Entrepreneur as Managing Director with proven abilities across all levels of organizational management with commitment to excellence having more than 20+ years of experience at different Organizations with remarkable decision-making and multi-tasking abilities. Innovative and driven with strong technical background with natural leadership talent, analytical and problem-solving expertise. Strengths in strategic planning, efficiency and team building. Offering excellent judgment, strong listening skills and a deep understanding of business operations.

Work Experience

CEO & Managing Director

May 2011 – July 2021 Astroshakthi Productions, Bangalore, KA

- Action-oriented, entrepreneurial, adaptable and innovative approach to business planning passion, idealism, integrity, positive attitude, mission-driven and self-directed.
- Experience in building the Company by increasing its assets and operations, developing its personnel and helping to set & attain business goals and objectives.
- Aligned organizational objectives with Company mission, increasing revenue, profit and business growth by collaboratively developing integrated strategies.

- Strategic planning, assess its structure, operations, policies, staffing, business model and funding requirements and make adjustments as appropriate.
- Comfort in managing various tasks simultaneously, ranging from the strategic to administrative, with proven ability to synthesize, prioritize and act.
- Experience in developing, planning and implementing successful strategies.
- Experience in marketing, sales, finance, HR, performance management principles, public relations and fundraising.
- Developed innovative sales and marketing strategies to facilitate business expansion.
- In-depth knowledge to read analyzes and interprets financial reports and legal documents.
- Experience in preparing all and any kind of legal documents as per the requirement.
- Responsible for the procurement and maintenance of & accounting for all working capital, merchandise and equipment of the Company.
- Developed strategies to build talent, by establishing programs and support systems for the recruitment, hiring, training, evaluation, retention and succession planning for all employees of the Company.
- Interviewed, supervised and motivated all staff members to achieve optimal productivity.
- Developed and maintained a positive relationship with funders, donors, policymakers, colleagues and anyone else who would have an impact on the life of the organization.
- Manages business operations with an emphasis on implementing initiatives to increase profits through performance and future-focused productivity improvements.
- Ability to maximize services with limited resources along with effective budget planning.
- Ensure the organization's complicity with legal and business ethics.

- Drove performance initiatives, facilitating 90% revenue increase.
- Strong in negotiation skills negotiated a business deal worth of \$100 Millions in Company's favor.

CEO & Managing Director

July 2009 – May 2011 KSN Properties, Bangalore, KA

- Strategic thinker with an entrepreneurial spirit, capable of moving a small organization to new levels.
- Managed and led team of 25 employee's focused on improving sales initiatives.

- Work collaboratively with the staff to develop and implement programs to achieve organizational goals.
- Strengthen and creatively leverage the use of technology in all aspects of the organization's work.
- In depth knowledge of all rules and regulations about different properties in state.
- Generate and manage lists of properties for sale.
- Perform comparative market analysis to estimate properties value.
- Promote sales through news paper advertisements and listing properties on internet.
- Provide information regarding legal, guidelines, rates, specifications and property availability to customers.
- Intermediate negotiation processes between seller and buyer, ensuring a fair and honest dealing.
- Provide guidance and assist sellers and buyers in marketing and purchasing property for the right price under the best terms & conditions.
- Responsible for compliance with all Company policies and regulatory agencies.

 Increased business profits upto 80% by streamlining processes and trimming unnecessary positions.

CEO & Managing Director

Sept 2006 – July 2009 Ramanashree Infosystems, Bangalore, KA

- Develop technical training courses for all levels (beginner, intermediate and advanced).
- Prepare educational material (e.g. design manuals and books).
- Explain the subject in a very easy language and understandable method to the students.
- Familiarity with hiring practices and stages screening, interview, assessment and on boarding.
- Experience in using recruiting software and social networks for recruiting.
- Share job ads on various job websites like LinkedIn, Face book, Monster, Indeed, Naukri and Times jobs.
- Manage all communication with candidates from the moment they apply until they get onboard.

• Trained, Educated for more than 500+ students and have placed them in many Companies.

Managing Partner & President

Feb 2001 – Sept 2006 RGR Infosys, Bangalore, KA

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Develop efficient strategies and business plans for all marketing aspects pricing, advertising, branding and product launching and product promotion etc.
- Assist in organizing of promotional events and traditional or digital campaigns.
- Plan and execute initiatives to reach the target audience through appropriate channels like e-mail & TV etc.
- Generating sales revenue from various sources of marketing efforts.
- Serve as the first point of contact for all customers seeking technical assistance over the phone or email.
- Follow up with clients to ensure their IT systems are fully functional after troubleshooting.
- Manage all on-site installations, repair and maintenance.

Key Achievements

• Increased revenue by over 135% in 5 years time span.

Managing Partner

April 1996 – Feb 2001 RGR Technologies, Bangalore, KA

- Entrepreneurial and Organizational qualities and skills.
- Analyze business requirements of all customers for their new systems, software's and applications needs.
- Build or Assemble custom made Systems, according to customer's requirement.

- Experience in installation, integration and configuring hardware's & software's like printers, network cards, graphic Cards and other peripheral devices etc.
- Assist Customers in solving technical problems when they arise, over the phone or pager.
- Building good relationships with all kinds of vendors and customers.
- Familiarity with various operating systems (e.g. Windows, Windows NT, Windows 2000, Red hat Linux and Unix).

• Increased clientele database by 20% every year, which grew net profits by 30% every year.

Education

MBA / Master of Business Administration

Dublin University, California, USA

Completion: 2005

Relevant Coursework: Organization Management, Business Management, Marketing Management, Finance Management, HR Management, Economics, Corporate Finance, Managerial Accounting, Financial Accounting, Financial Analysis, Multinational Accounting, Auditing International Finance and Management Information Systems.

Bachelor of Science

ABSS College, Delhi University, INDIA

Graduation: 2000

Skills & Endorsements

- 1. Organizational
- 2. Business Knowledge & Development
- 3. Business Analysis & Intelligence
- 4. Business Operations & Strategy Planning

- 5. Leadership & Management
- 6. Accounting & Finance Management
- 7. Calculated Risk Management
- 8. Time & Risk Management
- 9. Analytical & Budgeting
- 10. Public & Media Relations
- 11. Training & Scheduling
- 12. Interpersonal & Written Communication
- 13. Critical Thinking & Easily Adaptable
- 14. Decision-Making & Public Speaking
- 15. Negotiation & Presentation
- 16. Problem Solving & Teamwork
- 17. Determination & Conceptual
- 18. Creative Thinking & Planning
- 19. Efficiency & Delegation
- 20. Collaboration

Core Skills

Marketing, Sales, Financial Management, Budgeting, ERP Systems, Supply Chain Management, CRM, HR (HCM), Web Development, HTML, Digital Marketing, Cloud Architecture & Technology, Oracle & Database Management, Windows 7, Red hat Linux, Technical and IT Skills.

Certifications

- Oracle Certified ERP Master in Manufacturing Oracle University, USA
- Completion 1999
- Grade A+

Languages

• English, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil and Telugu – *Read, Write and Speak*.

Other Activities

- Movie Producer & Director, Member of Karnataka Film Chamber of Producer's Association.
- Volunteered to build Homeless Shelter. Led a drive to raise donations thru Crowd Funding.